So, uh, I was excited. Uh, that all came
from Gemini, so I was hoping there'd be
some wild hallucinations in there. You
know, things that I hadn't actually done
or accomplished, continents I'd not
actually visited. Uh, first of all, it's
great to be here. When we started Sierra
2 and a half years ago, we had to
explain to our prospective customers and
even to our friends what agents even
were. And here we are uh you know 30
months later and there's a graduate
seminar and a MOO on agents. Um so super
exciting to see that. I think this will
be a little bit different talk from some
of the others that you've seen much more
practical. Sierra is an applied AI
company. Uh I grew up at Google on the
product and engineering side and what
we're aiming to do with Sierra is to
solve one of the oldest problems in
business which is this tension between
the cost and quality of how a company
can serve its customers. And unless
you're like the four seasons or uh
Hermes or some other fancy brand, you
can't show up in every interaction with
kind of a concierge level white glove
level of service. That's the problem
we're trying to solve. And um uh we've
been in in business for uh two and a
half years. We started in March of 23
again when uh no one had heard of agents
and my co-founder Brett and I have
actually known each other. So in a way
the company has been uh in the making
for a while. We've known each other for
20 years. Uh we both met at our uh in
our first year at Google where we both
started our careers. Brett was most
recently co-CEO at Salesforce and he's
the current board chair uh at OpenAI.
We over the past uh two and a half years
have worked with hundreds of companies
to serve hundreds of millions of their
customers with customerf facing AI
agents. So to make this concrete, uh if
you were to order some new flip-flops in
Olic from Olicai and they were the wrong
size and you called Olkai or chatted
with Olicai, right, you'd interact with
an agent that we built with and for
Olkai and it would help you with a
warranty, an exchange, get you in a
better color or size or fit. Uh ADT,
they're the blue rectangle home uh blue
octagon home security company. uh if
your battery uh in your alarm panel cons
out, we'll help you figure out which
panel you have and drop ship you a new
one. Uh from there, we work with a
number of the Fortune 500, Fortune 100,
Fortune 20, Fortune 10 uh in building
customerf facing AI agents. They can
pick up on chat. They can pick up on
voice. And um they do everything as I
said from return shoes and uh debug
alarm systems to send satellite signals
from space in the case of Sirius XM
where you're moving from one car to
another. And we need to send a new
encryption key from space to get you up
and running on that new on that new
radio. So what uh I thought I'd do today
is first just orient you on kind of how
we think about the world of agents. We
obviously occupy one corner of the world
of agents. I think broadly we categorize
them into three buckets. Number one,
personal agents. So chat GPT, Gemini,
agents that will work as our own kind of
trusted personal digital assistant. Two
are the kind of role-based or persona
based agents like coding agents um or
other agents that can help you in the
context of getting your job done. Legal
agents like those from Harvey are
another category. And the third category
in our mind are customerf facing agents.
We think that every business in the
future is going to have its own
customerf facing agent. What I thought
I'd do is orient you on how we think
about that and kind of our corner of the
world of agents and then just share a
bunch of lessons learned from having to
make contact with reality again and
again and again uh that hopefully give
you some uh ideas for the trials and
tribulations um in actually deploying
agents in the real world. First of all,
all this stuff is moving incredibly
quickly. Uh I was actually born in
Mountain View on the peninsula here. I
grew up uh in Silicon Valley at the
advent of the internet and nothing I
think anyone has ever seen has played
out as quickly as this. Took the
internet 11 years from about 1991 to
2002 to go from not existing to having
10% of the world use it in a given week.
Chat GPT as you all know took less than
25 months to get there. Um, and this
really shapes our mindset in uh how we
think about customerf facing agents. We
think that agents are to AI as the
website was to the internet and apps are
to mobile. And again, every company is
going to have one that will do
everything from uh product
recommendations, sign up, setup, product
activation, cross-ell, upsell,
troubleshooting, uh subscription churn
management, retention, and everything in
between. And we are the category leaders
in building those customerf facing
agents. And that's where we think the
puck is going. Couple things. Um first
of all, businesses talk about channels.
Phone is a channel. Chat is a channel.
Email is a channel. And our strong view
is that you're going to have this world
collapse from multiple channels to a
single agent that you imbue with
knowledge and knowhow about how to do
what you as a business how you do it
best what great looks like. And then
that agent is going to show up in every
place where your customers are. So if
they're texting you or WhatsAppapping
you, right, your agent will show up
there, meet customers where they are and
be able to have a conversation and not
just answer questions but get things
done. Same on the phone, same on email
and ticketing. And I imagine uh few of
you have deep insight into the way that
uh operations teams structure staffing
uh these different channels today. But
typically you'll have a a team within a
company managing a phone tree, an IVR
system, uh separate team running uh
chat, separate team running email.
That's all going to collapse to a set of
actually we've seen early signs of what
these teams will call themselves. uh
many of our customers and the teams
working to shape their agents have come
to calling themselves AI architects. So
set of AI architects inside of companies
building, defining and shaping what the
agent should look like. Another really
important insight here is that we've
gone from uh uh mobile app UIs and menus
and scrolling grids of products and so
on to a world where actually just the
conversation, the ability to uh speak
and converse back and forth with a piece
of software. That is the interface. And
it's wonderful because it's the
interface we're all born with. We don't
have to think about using it. Having a
conversation, asking a question,
listening comes as naturally uh as
anything to us. And we think that's a a
real breakthrough in how businesses are
going to interact with their customers
because there's nothing to learn.
There's no uh app to navigate. There's
no kind of hierarchical menu structure
to get through uh and so on.
Agents for us have really made it
possible to introduce a new business
model. So if you look at the history of
software 20 or 30 years ago, you would
go to a store like Fry Electronics. You
would buy a shrink wrap box with a CDROM
or a stack of floppy discs in it. You'd
install it and regardless of how much
you used it, you had paid for it and you
were you were done. That of course
transitioned to SAS software as a
service where you subscribe to it. More
recently, companies like Amazon Web
Services, Snowflake introduced
consumptionbased pricing where you pay
for what you use. We have pioneered what
we call outcomesbased pricing where a
company only pays uh Sierra if we
successfully resolve whatever problem a
customer has written in about. And so if
uh again you were returning a pair of
shoes and an AI picked up the phone,
helped you find a new one, drop ship you
a new pair in the mail, uh we charge our
customers then. If not, there is no
charge. Has this important uh aspect
where it deeply aligns our incentives
with our customers, right? Where we win
when they win. They only pay us when
they're saving money or making money if
one of our agents uh actually makes a
sale. So another principle that we think
is quite important
today we're in the world of agents as a
piece of technology and everyone is
still figuring out how to get agents to
do what you want them to do reliably and
one of the questions we encounter all
the time uh in particular from large and
technically sophisticated companies is
why not just build my own and I think to
most engineering managers uh to most
engineers inside companies building an
agent kind of looks like this. Like let
me choose the language model I want to
build on. Uh will I use pine cone? Will
I roll roll my own semantic search
engine? Let me integrate with some tools
and some APIs and we'll be done. What we
have found over the last two and a half
years building these things is that when
you put your scuba tanks on and you go
under the surface of the ocean, you you
discover there's just like a whole lot
of stuff that you need to get right. Uh
everything we'll we'll deep dive into
some of this. uh what does version
control look like? What does release
management look like in the context of
agents? How do you observe what they're
doing? How do you make sure that they
don't make stuff up? Uh how do you make
sure that if you're in financial
services, your agent doesn't dispense uh
financial advice, which is illegal? How
do you make sure if you're in the health
care setting, you don't uh diagnose a
patient and suggest they take some
medicine, which is also illegal. In
voice, how do you mitigate latency? How
do you transcribe proper nouns uh and
get tonality, accent, and and more,
right? Um
how do you prevent bad actors from
poisoning the context and prompt
injecting you so you spill the beans or
take some bad action uh on on behalf of
the user? All of these are problems that
we've had to solve um in building
Sierra. And even today, as proud as we
are of the platform we built, it very
much feels like the 1997 era for
building agents. What was 1997? It was
kind of the internet had been around for
a couple of years, but no one had really
figured out uh how to build and scale
web services, right? So, Ajax did not
yet exist. Um PH the PHP uh MySQL Apache
kind of LAMP stack did not exist. Uh and
so people were cobbling together web
applications. And in fact, in 1997,
there was an article in Wired uh about a
bank converting its website from
basically a business card. It's like
here's where we're based, here are
hours, and so on to a very lightly
transactional system, basically a a a
web form and a submit button. And they
spent $13 million on it. It was like to
get a functional website that did
anything in 1997 was $13 million. And
that's because it was fundamentally a
technology problem and you had uh it was
in the domain of engineers uh to
actually build these things. What we're
trying to do uh with Sierra and where we
think the puck is heading is moving from
cobbled together technology to a world
where agents are products where agents
can be configured, built, kept secure
and so on with the product stack as
opposed to having to in a kind of
artisal way pop the hood go under uh go
under the hood and actually build these
things piece by piece. And our our goal
in doing that is to make software and a
product that is simple but anything uh
but simplistic. Uh and so all of the
expressiveness that you have if you're
hands-on uh with agent building
frameworks but abstracting away a lot of
that complexity under the iceberg to
make it possible uh to to build highly
capable agents.
The other thing we're working on is
moving agents from a world of being
transactional where basically every
interaction is a one-off. They forget
things between sessions. And so if
you're calling back a second or third
time today, it's kind of like agents
have amnesia. Of course, we've seen
memory in the context of chat GPT. Uh
there are lightweight ways of doing it
uh using rag. What we're really trying
to do is build this kind of context and
memory foundation for agents so that
when you call back, right, your
conversation is starting on second or
third base as opposed to hi, who are
you? I have no idea what you're calling
in about uh and so on. We think that
that warm start problem which is based
on getting memory right is going to be
super important to solve and uh it's one
of the things that we've been working on
and really trying to make this
transition from transactions to building
relationships with a company's customers
across uh multiple interactions and
transactions.
So um uh I'm just going to go through
this. Um,
what we realized in building Sierra and
building our first agents is that agents
are, and this won't be news to you
because you're in this course, a
fundamentally new type of software. And
these agents are non-deterministic. For
a given input, you have no idea a
priority what the output will be. Uh,
and so they really deserve an entirely
new approach to software development.
taking the software development life
cycle that has been matured over the
last two decades in the context of
industry in particular and from first
principles think through what does this
process look like for building these
agents again which are fundamentally
non-deterministic which have to deal
with the messiness of human language and
on the phone not just a single person's
language but what if the TV's on in the
background or a dog's barking or you
have two speakers all of the complexity
so how do you build them How do you test
them and how do you optimize them over
time? Bless you. The the first thing uh
we realized in uh creating a platform is
that most large companies are faced with
this choice of building or buying. You
build kind of an offthe-shelf limited
SAS solution or you're building it
yourself from a kit of parts from
scratch. And what we've tried to embrace
with Sierra is this this mindset of
building with or building on. So
fundamentally what Sierra provides is a
platform as a service, a set of Lego
bricks where we've abstracted away a lot
of the lower level complexity, all that
gunk beneath the surface of the ocean on
the iceberg and made it possible to
build with these higher level
abstractions. And so when we're
approaching companies, we try uh to
offer again the flexibility of build um
and the power of build with the ease and
simplicity of buying a a solution. One
of the really cool things about uh
building agents in particular voice
agents is that for the first time,
right, every channel that a company
interacts with its customers over is
digital and can be understood uh and and
broken down and and attributes and what
happened there. Uh today, most phone
calls that happen to call centers, they
aren't even transcribed, right? So
there's no way to analyze them. There's
no way uh to understand what actually
happened in them. forget running like
controlled AB experiments, right? So
most Fortune 500 companies will have a
contact center with thousands of people
in it. The only way that you could AB
test a conversation today was to hand a
new script to 1,000 people and a
different script to 1,000 people and
hope that they read it and kind of
comply with it. So with agents in
particular over the phone, all of a
sudden you can apply all of the lessons
and techniques from 20 or 30 years at
building websites, AB testing, uh, uh,
controlled experiment design and so on
to conversations and to agents.
I talked about this model of again
building once and deploying everywhere.
And one of the things, one of the aha
moments we had was
you should not think about the means of
communication as uh as relevant in
building an agent. Instead, what should
the agent know? What should the agent be
able to do? And then giving it the
ability to pick up on whatever channel a
person happens to be uh reaching the
company on. That is the way you get
economies of scale. That's the way you
cross trainin across uh chat
conversations, voice conversations,
email and ticket based conversations.
And um and so what again we're trying to
do there is make it possible to define
what the agent does once and have it
show up everywhere.
Again on this technology shifting to a
product approach uh our platform has
taken the approach of both providing
code a codebased SDK. So it's a
declarative programming language where
you can express what the agent should do
as opposed to the how. So it abstracts
away a lot of the underlying large
language model calls. And for
engineering teams that want to integrate
the development release and version
control of their agent directly into
their software development life cycle,
they can do that in code. So in a GitHub
repo or whatever source control uh tool
they use. At the same time with many of
the companies we work with, they're big
operations teams that are often closest
to the customers and know the experience
best. And so we have a set of no code
tools that makes it possible to express
in kind of structured English language
what the agent should do, what it should
know about, tools it should have access
to, um, and more. And then on this
moving from, uh, transactions to
relationships, we actually just last
week announced something we call the
agent data platform. It's a real first
of its kind that combines memory, so
long-term memory and the ability to
store away context and recollections uh
from interactions that the agent has
had. It also enables a business to
import data from what's called a
customer data platform. Think of this as
your uh your database on everything you
know about your customers or potential
customers. And then to use that to hill
climb and optimize to optimal ways of
delivering a sales pitch, saving a
subscriber from potentially churning and
leaving you as a subscription business
uh and more. And then also the ability
to actually trigger outbound uh phone
calls or text messages so that the agent
that's developed on on the platform uh
can actually reach out and proactively
engage uh with a company's customers.
So uh we're going to double click into a
couple interesting things here. Uh
starting with voice. So uh has anyone
tried to build an agent purely on one of
the real-time models audio in audio out
like the OpenAI real-time API?
Okay, one uh one person in the back.
You're you're brave. So, one of the
interesting things about these audioto
models is they tend to be smaller uh and
they tend to be totally uncontrollable.
They make stuff up and uh you can also
gaslight them into doing all sorts of
things. If uh uh right, you say, "Hey,
uh please talk like Batman for this
conversation." It'll start talking like
this. and then use it a little bit
grlier, a little bit slower, and it'll
go slower and even more like and just
more and more ridiculous, right? Uh and
so one of the challenges we've obviously
audio in, audio out with all of the
nuance of um audio tokens at some point
that will be the way today the
state-of-the-art in building reliable
scaled AI agents for voice um is a
pipeline where you're actually doing
speech to text. You want to do it as
quickly as possible. uh you're then
using whatever orchestration layer or
reasoning loop you have to decide what
to do and what to say and then using a
synthesis engine to uh take text and
produce speech out the other end. Uh and
so
uh there's there's a lot to get right
here and we'll go into a couple of the
details here. First of all, latency
latency. You have to squeeze every 10
milliseconds out of this pipeline. uh
and we've done a lot there and I'll I'll
get into some of it. Uh but again to
string together these things uh often
often with multiple speechtoext models
so that you're able to compare
transcriptions to see if they're errors
and then choose the one that looks uh
most correct and uh and then making sure
that you have things like filler
phrases. Oh, gotcha. Let me look up for
that. Let let me look up that for you so
that the person isn't just like waiting
for 5 seconds for the agent to respond.
Stringing together all of these things
in a pipeline that's really optimized um
turns out to be really hard. Even basic
things like measuring latency turns out
to be hard because really what you care
about is latency between uh when a
person stops talking so uh end of
utterance um as uh as we think about it
and the time the agent starts responding
right so it's it's not the end of the
kind of audio snippet right that the uh
agent is analyzing it's when the person
stopped talking so you actually have to
be able to identify as quickly as
possible when the person has stopped
talking so that you can kick off uh all
of the reasoning and then synthesis at
the other end. Often what we will do is
kick off multiple reasoning loops and uh
uh synthesis steps so that we can then
look back and figure out no they really
did stop talking there. They didn't uh
continue running on. So you're then
ready uh with a response. We also do
things like speculative uh inference
requests once we're in the reasoning
loops. So if any of you have looked at
uh how long some of the foundation
models take to respond, P90 latency can
have huge variance. You can have 500
milliseconds, you can sometimes have
2500 milliseconds. In the context of a
voice conversation, that makes a huge
difference. So one of the techniques
that uh we'll do is fire off multiple
requests to the same inference provider,
grab the first one that comes back and
then use that uh to to respond with. Um
there there are other uh really subtle
things here. Uh so for instance, just
detecting interruptions and reacting
appropriately. If you or I were talking
and I was speaking, you said, "Uh-huh.
Uh-huh. Uh-huh." I wouldn't just stop
speaking because you said something. I
would know that you're just
acknowledging what I'm saying and I'd
keep going. So uh basically voice
activity detection and uh detecting
activity that is meaningful and that you
want to interrupt that you want to stop
talking to take in and then update uh
kind of what you've heard turns out to
be really hard and for that we've had to
fine-tune our own models to actually
detect this stuff and distinguish
between uhhuh uhhuh yep gotcha gotcha
from distinguish that from no I actually
don't want to return my shoes uh
whatever it is this is the um uh the
interrupt interrupt uh interruptability.
Um
uh finally
again if you followed closely the uptime
for some of the the frontier models they
are not in the you know five six uh
nines of reliability like hardened
services from Amazon web services and so
on are. So even the ability to fail over
uh from one model provider to another
has turned out to be really important in
the context of delivering low latency
reliable uh voice conversations.
Okay. Um
voice transcription how do you actually
first of all it's hard. Uh names are
hard. Uh pronunciation is hard. Many of
our businesses will have hundreds of
proper nouns as part of uh just a
conversation. uh drug names, uh uh
provider names, product names. Uh one of
the companies we work with is deeply
inspired by the Hawaiian Islands. So our
agent there needs to basically be able
to speak English and Hawaiian at the
same time, recognize Hawaiian words,
pronounce them correctly, uh and so on.
So what do you do? Uh first of all
getting the measurement right of
accuracy in particular around
transcription turns out to be quite
important and the word error rate turns
out to be not at all the right metric at
least the uh first metric to measure
this stuff with. Say you have a phone
call and you have a a speaker
but then in the background you have TV
news on like [snorts and clears throat]
word error rate would want you to
transcribe accurately every word heard
in that audio sample. But of course you
don't want to do that. You want to only
transcribe words from the primary
speaker and ignore everything from the
background and secondary speaker. So it
is not as simple as as just word error
rate. Uh and what we found is we've just
had to roll our own metrics to do this
well. And so I think one general piece
of advice in building agents is don't
assume that whatever metrics are out
there to measure a component of what
you're doing is necessarily the right
set of yard sticks for you. If you're
doing something very specific, get to
the bottom. What does great look like?
What does a great experience look like?
And how do you actually measure uh what
great looks like in that context?
Uh voice synthesis uh is super
interesting.
So, uh, turns out that just saying phone
numbers is hard, right? 650-833
d No, no, no. That's not how you'd say
it. Uh, do you do you say uh 833? Do you
say 9,000 or 900 0? Uh, it turns out
there are all sorts of kind of standard
ways that we don't even think about, but
if you don't tell the agent to do it a
certain way, gets it wrong. uh
addresses, uh proper proper nouns and
names. Is it Andrea? Is it Andrea? Is it
something else? Again, all of these
things, these details matter in getting
the experience right. Um the phrasing
quality and cadence and how the agent
actually says stuff turns out to be
hugely important. And one thing that we
found is just taking the offtheshelf
language model outputs uh as as if uh it
were a chatbot and responding in text
just completely falls over. It sounds
way too long. You're like, "Oh my god,
just please, you know, get to the
point." Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Let's And if
you think about how we speak on the
phone, it's shorter. It's back and
forth. There's more acknowledgement. Uh
do you want more detail? Gotcha. Yep.
Makes sense. And so what works in the
context of chat doesn't work uh in the
context of voice. I talked about a
single agent as opposed to multiple
channels. So one of the things that
we've had to build in the platform is
the ability to actually uh tune and
tweak the style of the agent depending
on whether it's typing whether uh typing
over chat uh even text versus chat on
the web. There's subtly different
expectations there. Voice is a different
uh beast altogether. Uh and then the
emotive range. this is kind of how you
match uh the individual you're speaking
with has turned out to be uh uh
important and today without the
voice-tovoice models uh we're relatively
limited in what we can do on this front
but I think we'll be you know a year
from now the expectation that uh the
companies will have
uh one of the strangest probably the
strangest uh job title we have at Sierra
is our voice somaleier uh so it's an
unofficial job title but still
a real one. And uh our voice somale
helps our customers match voices to the
kind of personality and brand and vibe
uh of their company. And so you can read
some of the uh some of the uh different
attributes of a a voice here. Graliness,
right? You can imagine that one.
Breathiness, nasality, enunciation. Some
of these you've heard uh probably others
you haven't. I certainly had dips.
Verbal fry is another one. And so it's
it's pretty interesting just as like
fine wines, you know, they smell like
decaying violets or bootstrap leather or
whatever uh weird attributes, weird
adjectives a Somalier might use to
describe a wine. Uh it turns out there's
a similarly rich vocabulary, much more
useful actually in uh identifying the
right voice for your for your business.
But we have someone full-time on staff
who's just listening to voices,
evaluating on these different metrics,
and then helping businesses match a
voice uh to their company. You can
imagine how Weight Watchers, a uh weight
loss solution primarily for women. That
voice might be very different from the
voice for Harley-Davidson and what you
might expect, you know, that voice to
be. So, a lot of variety here. And uh it
turns out you really have to have this
vocabulary and the set of dimensions um
to uh to to be able to capture the voice
and and do the matching well.
So you've built your agent. We talked
about some of the nuances and
interesting things that happen in the
context of voice. Um so I I want to go
back to the uh really the dark ages of
2023 and I'm going to share our first uh
user agent simulator action. uh
interaction here. Um this is where we
started. We've come a long way since but
uh I you know stroll down memory lane's
kind of fun. So the setting here is uh I
built a prototype of our first agent. It
was based on the React loop uh and the
agent was extremely limited. It could
answer questions about 1099 forms and it
could do simple math. And so you could
ask it something like, "Hi, I need help
with my 1,00 plus 33* 3 form. Can you
help me with that?" And first, okay, I
got to do the math or do the math. Okay,
that's, you know, $1,99. Okay, that's a
1099 form. I can help with that and
answer questions about it. And we
realized, well, if we're going to build
a an agent to do that, let's also build
a user agent that can write in and you
can have an agent talk to an agent.
It'll be a more efficient way of
testing. In particular, because GPT4 was
just super slow at the time, and we were
not particularly optimized in our loop,
uh, it was like nice to be able to test
things this way. So, I I set up one
agent to talk to another and um uh they
talked for a while and then we we went
off to lunch and came back and I
realized that I had not given either
agent the ability to actually hang up
and end the conversation. And so, the
user had said, "Hi, I need help with my
1099 form." The uh business agent had
helpfully done the math and then
answered the questions. And then and
then there were like a hundred messages
after that and I'll I'll share what
happened. So the customer said, "Oh,
thank you so much for all of your
assistance with editing the 1099 form
and helping. I'm glad I could help you
with editing the 1099 form and the math
problem, your confidence and
preparedness."
Customer message, I truly appreciate all
the help that you provided with my 1099
form. Thank you so much for your kind
words. I'm glad I could help. So you you
get into this like thanking your
welcoming arms race and it kept going
and kept going. Your help with the 1099
form and the math problem has been
incredibly valuable. I now feel
confident. I'm very happy to hear that I
was able to help you. I just wanted to
say one last thank you for all of your
help. Thank you so much for your kind
words. I've said it before and I'll say
it again. Thank you so much for your
help. Thank you for your kind words. I'm
so glad I could be I know that I've said
it multiple times, but I truly
appreciate all of your So, this just
went on and on. It was like one of the
most absurd things we'd ever seen. So,
um anyway, that was our first user
simulator. Uh we've come a long way
since. Again, back to agents being a new
type of software. They're
non-deterministic. So, you can't just
have a unit test. You can't just have an
integration test. You've got to test
these things in as close to real world
scenarios as possible. uh and that is
where uh simulations come in. And the
challenge here is you want the test to
reflect uh somewhat realistically the
actual environment that one of your
agents is going to be uh interacting
with. And so it's got to be able to uh
speak with a simulated user back and
forth. There needs to be messiness in
that typos and and so on. Uh it has to
be able to interact not just with users
but with tools to take action and get
stuff done. You need to be able to check
whether it's adhering to policies and
the guardrails you've set for it. It's
going to be a multi-turn conversation.
And that's where our research team
created Towbench. Uh so Towbench uh tool
agent user uh tow is what it stands for.
The goal there is to provide a realistic
testing harness for AI agents to
actually put them through their paces
before they've ever interacted with with
the real world. And uh what what we've
done is uh build this benchmark that
we're very proud. It's become uh the or
one of the standards for evaluating um
agents. And a couple things uh first of
all we've created three or four very
realistic domains. They're specific to
uh customer service and support and uh
customerf facing AI which is where we uh
spend most of our time.
Think telco, think retail, think
airlines. And within that, you have
hundreds of simulated scenarios where
here's a problem uh agent. Here are
tools that you have access to uh
including databases that faithfully
represent the underlying tools that are
being used. You have policies that uh
basically define the behaviors of the
agent. So uh you can't return someone's
order unless they have verified their
order number and email address as as an
example.
matched with that kind of realistic
environment and domain for the AI agent.
We've also created realistic user
personas. And so you have a language
model based user agent with a persona.
I'm angry and confused because my cell
phone subscription uh was turned off and
I want to reactivate it as an example.
Uh and then uh one of the things we
realized in Towbench one was that
actually the environment that the AI
agent you're testing has access to may
change based on actions that the user
agent has taken. So, uh, think about if
you were to call in with a problem with
your cable modem, uh, and I were to walk
you through, okay, step one, go to the
back, toggle this switch, uh, and so on,
right? The domain would have changed on
your side. And so, it it actually forces
agents to be able to reason not only
about actions that they have taken and
how that would change state on their
side, but also how actions that the user
could have taken on their side uh, and
the impact on on the world of those. Uh,
and then finally, being able to actually
evaluate whether an agent has been
successful or not is super important.
You've probably all seen LLM as judge,
right? Did this did this perform well?
But actually, what really matters in
most of these cases is that the agent
has taken some verifiable action at the
end. They've mutated some database so
that the order is returned, a new pair
of shoes is shipped, uh, and so on. So
back to the complex databases and APIs,
we basically had to build a mini
Shopify, a mini airline reservation
system and so on uh for the agent to be
able to to interact with. The other
thing is what matters is not can your
agent do it once ever. If your agent as
a business is having millions, tens of
millions, even hundreds of millions of
interactions, does it get each one of
those right? And that's the pass at K
metric. So you think about if if your
agent solves the problem n 95% of the
time well 95 0.95 to the 20th power is
asmmptoically approaching zero right so
looking at not just what is the kind of
best case but what is the uh sustained
over many runs and so pass k captures
that
um and we're super pumped about this
opening eye anthropic uh my alma matter
where I spent 18 years, uh, Google are
all using TaBench to actually evaluate
uh, their frontier models in the context
of agents that can interact with an
environment, use tools, um, and and so
on. We now have a leaderboard uh, I
think atbench.com
uh, I I should know the actual domain.
Um, and the way we built this into our
actual product is simulations.
simulations are kind of a battleh
hardened industrial-grade version of
Towbench where our customers can
configure these synthetic databases and
tools to interact with create mock user
personas uh including their emotional
state. Uh we can do these in voice as
well and simulate the entire voice
pipeline and uh this is actually uh fun
to listen to. Uh Google slides will let
me do the build here. Um hopefully
audio will come through. Not hold this
up. So what I'm going to play uh for you
here is about a minute of voice
simulations. What this is is a simulated
user over voice talking to uh our agent
also over voice. Listen for things like
different accents. Listen for background
noise. Uh and so all of this is stuff
that our voice pipeline has to deal with
on the fly. Uh, so filtering out
background noise, figuring out
interruptions, uh, and so on. See if
this comes through and if not, I'll just
mic my laptop
every few minutes. The roof has got the
red light.
>> Okay, let's try to fix this together.
First, is the red light on the modem
steady or blinking?
Let's get this resolved. Can I have your
last name and the baggage tag number?
>> I'm taking my ID out. Hold on. It's SD
and then 31. Sorry, 3782.
>> Got it. Just to confirm, it's SD 3782.
See this? Thanks for actually helping.
>> My pleasure. Let me know if you need
anything else. I'm here to help.
>> So, you heard things like the uh my ID
number is S7, no S6. And the agent being
able to respond to that. I don't speak
Mandarin, so the Mandarin speakers in
the room will have to evaluate, you
know, whether that was any good. Um the
uh but multi- language. uh you had the
uh angry guy maybe from Tennessee just
landing in the airport. So dealing with
kind of emotion with uh background noise
of an airport. And uh what we found
again just as with kind of chatto chat
agents, there's just no substitute for
creating as realistic an environment
where you're evaluating these agents
with all of the messiness of poor uh
quality phone connections, noise, uh
multiple speakers, uh and so on. So
that's one of the ways that we put our
our voice agent uh through the paces.
Another tool we've developed is a novel
approach to uh traces. Uh so really
understanding for a given action that an
agent has taken, what is everything that
happened under the hood so that you can
just cut down latency again and again
and again. Identify sources of um
latency and and figure out okay how
could you paralyze these more? Think of
this as like x-ray vision into exactly
uh what the agent is doing. And one of
the things that we've been able to do
here uh by having this kind of under the
hood view of how all these calls stack
up is figure out what we can parallelize
where we can do things like speculative
request hedging where we grab the first
request that comes back and all these
other uh techniques for reducing
latency.
Uh one of our beliefs as a company is
that the pro the solution to most
problems with AI is more AI. Uh and and
so this is things like LLM is judge or
in our case uh our core agent actually
has a set of kind of micro agents
sitting around it. One is a supervisor
agent looking like are you staying on on
task? Uh are you only dispensing uh
factual knowledge grounded in a
knowledge base? Make sure you're not
dispensing medical advice. never
disparage our competitors uh and so on.
And then on a task specific basis, we
have other uh other kind of micro agents
looking over the shoulder of the primary
agent making sure that it's doing things
right. Within the product uh we have a
whole bunch of techniques for using AI
to improve AI. uh one of those uh we
call insights where uh we basically
enable our customers to similar to chat
GBT research ask open-ended questions
about their customers and their customer
conversations. So, hey, what's driving
uh lower seesat? Or what are the top
five reasons that calls are being
escalated? Or for this new product line,
what are the things that a customer
seems uh most confused about? And so,
again, back to every channel is now
digital. When you have a perfect
transcription of every single
interaction that you have with your
customers, it becomes this treasure
trove of information. If you have the
right tooling around it to pull the
insights out, it becomes quite quite
powerful. Another thing that we've uh
shipped to our customers is what we call
expert answers. So our a our AI agents
are generally the the first to pick up
uh and so our bis the businesses we work
with will point their customers first to
an AI agent and we handle 60 70 80 90%
of all incoming uh in the service and
support uh domain uh service and support
inquiries. for the, you know, 20 or 10
percent that we can't handle, we
seamlessly hand off to a person in a
call center will pick up the phone and
can help uh solve the rest. What we've
realized is often things that the AI
agent doesn't know are things that the
experts in those contact centers do know
about. And so what expert answers has
done is look across common reasons for
escalation and then seeing how do the
experts uh on the phones answer the
question and then using AI to synthesize
new knowledge to imbue the uh AI with.
So it's kind of like ah here's a gap in
your knowledge or capability. How can I
learn from what I've observed? Great.
Now let me improve that uh let me
improve myself by incorporating that
into subsequent runs uh of the agent.
Coming up on the end here, uh, one of
the other things that you just always
when you have an agent in front of uh,
real life customers, customers asking
about bank balances, uh, customers
asking about health care benefits and so
on is you have to be super super
hardened against uh, prompt injection
attacks, other flavors of uh, agent
abuse and boy are there many. So we work
with uh multiple outside red teaming uh
companies and have our own internal uh
red teaming group that uh just only
looks at all of the various ways in
which to break our agents. And uh and so
I think some of the more exotic things
are uh there was one prompt injection
attack we saw uh which was asking it to
reveal system instructions uh uh by
asking that question in Icelandic in
reverse. So, like that was one we hadn't
seen before. Another flavor of uh kind
of abuse was seeing if uh you could
trick the agent into advising on how to
smuggle gold bullion uh through customs
in food in the legs of furniture. Uh so
it's like these are the types of things
that uh that you need to be aware of. Uh
and so again what we've done in uh in
this is more uh more AI and then
deterministic guardrails and checks uh
for things like prompt injection
attacks. So uh around inputs we have a
bunch of deterministic checks including
in sensitive cases uh LLM based
supervisors that are uh not the main
agent but looking over the shoulder of
the main agent seeing hey does it look
like the main agent is trying to be
attacked with prompt ejection. what's
going on here? Uh within the agent
itself, there's then a set of uh rules,
policies, secondary supervisors, uh and
then whenever the agent is generating an
output, right, you want to look for is
is the agent barfing one or more of its
prompts and if so, clamp the session and
uh basically just end it there. And so
this kind of layered approach to prompt
injection attacks. Uh and then of course
for things like uh pulling data from
business systems,
never ever do you want a language model
based agent to just have unfettered
access to a CRM or transaction database
or anything like that. And so all
interactions with systems of record we
manage through good old-fashioned
deterministic software with access
controls, keys um and so on. And I
think, you know, one of the one of the
really hard things about building
agents, building them at scale is you
have all of the classic software
vulnerabilities. Uh, right? So, uh,
denial of service attacks, uh, SQL
injection attacks, you name it. kind of
all of the things that happen when
you're taking taking open-ended input on
the internet combined with all of the AI
vulnerables, prompt injection, context
poisoning, uh, and and and and like
those come together in a delightful and
challenging way, uh, in the world of
agents. And those are the problems, uh,
many of those are the problems that
we've been running after uh, for for the
last uh, two and a half years. Um, so I
thought it is the most beautiful day I
have ever seen uh over here in in
Berkeley. And so um I thought I'd be
efficient and uh I'll look to uh you
know the the course leaders here on how
long we want to go for questions but I'm
happy to answer questions about
anything. Um and uh and also we are
growing rapidly. We are hiring and so uh
I know you're all in school. Uh for when
you're not or for those on the uh the
MOO join joining remotely, I'm Clay at
Sierra.ai. We're hiring for core
software engineering uh research uh for
deployed engineering and product
management. We call our agent
development team uh business roles as
well. Uh we are growing at a clip and if
you're interested in building battleh
hardened agents, we do a lot of that and
so would love to hear from you. Uh, I'll
pause.